A lot of times the linebackers can make the right reads, they can step up in the proper gaps, they can do all the right things, they can shed the blocks, but they have to make sure they finish off the tackles properly.
If not, all that other hard work was for nothing.
So, what we want to talk about is how to come up in that gap, break down, stay low, and make a good hit.
(video demo) He's going to attack his gap, he's going to meet the blocker head on.
The first thing he has to do is get low and shed that block.
Once he sheds the block he has to take on this guy.
He wants his head to the outside and he wants to hit the running back low.
He doesn't want to come up and make a high hit on a running back because a running back will bounce off of him.
Once he's hit low, he wants to wrap up, keep his feet moving and drive through the tackle.
If the running back is able to keep his feet moving and get lower leverage, he'll take our linebacker and push him for a positive gain.
We want to hit him and push for a negative gain.
This is what it looks like live when you have a proper tackling technique (video demo).
He came in, he hit low and made a good stop in the backfield and he finished off the tackle giving no hope to our running back.